

APARAJEETA BHATTACHARYA <u>D.O.B</u>. −

27/04/1977

MOBILE -

(+91) 8240980061, (+91) 9748443602

EMAIL -

aparajeeta27@gmail.com

ADDRESS -

B-3/3, Karunamoyee Housing Estate Salt Lake City, Sector – 2, Bidhannagar, Dist. – 24 Parganas (N), Kolkata – 700 091

SUMMARY:

A Corporate Legal Professional with greater than 14 Years of Post-Enrolment Experience in **Magma Fincorp Ltd**. (NBFC) which is renamed as **Poonawalla Fincorp Ltd**. (NBFC). My corporate achievements include recognitions / promotions in the organisations with complete dedication and loyalty that I have worked for.

EDUCATION:

- Completed Schooling and College level from Calcutta (West Bengal) in the years 1994 and 1997 respectively.
- Completed M.Com in University of Calcutta in the year 1999, West Bengal.
- Completed the Three (3) Year LLB Course in the Year 2006 from the University of Gauhati, Assam.
- Completed the Two (2) Year LLM Course in the Year 2014 from the Mahatma Gandhi University, Kottayam, Kerala.

ENROLMENT:

• Enrolled as an Advocate under Bar Council of West Bengal in the year 2008.

AWARD/RECOGNITION:

- CATALYST AWARD (Certificate of Recognition) received from Poonawalla Fincorp Ltd. in Q1, FY 2023.
- CERTIFICATE OF APPRECIATION received from Magma Fincorp Ltd. in the year August 2018.

WORK EXPERIENCE (LITIGATION):

April, 2022 till date:

Promoted as Manager (Litigation) in Poonawalla Fincorp Ltd. The core job includes dealing against case - Civil, Consumer, Criminal Litigations in Courts, Fora, Tribunals & coordination with PAN India team. Report directly to the National Legal Head (Litigation).

Key Activities:

- Ownership of all Contentious & Non-Contentious Legal Issues.
- Crisis Management
- Handling Internal & External Legal Audit & Liaison with Statutory & Regulatory Authorities
- Legal Training
- Implement strategy to close the cases against the senior management by virtue of rigours, disciplined and meticulous follow up with field team members and empanelled advocates.
- Empanelment & Management of Specialised External Lawyers / Law Firms and Rationalisation of Pay Out Grid
- Advise on initiation of legal case for Statutory and Regulatory Compliances in accordance with audit report & to conduct review of substantial action taken in fraud matter within quest possible time & recovery efforts made against them.
- Day to Day Support & Advisory Work and Resolution of Queries from Management, Business Functions / Verticals and Branches on all Legal Issues
- · Day to Day Advice on Risk Management Strategy
- Analysing the impact of various ranges of decree /order passed against the company by different court/forum/tribunals and implementing strategies for dispute resolution including Conciliation, Mediation, Lok Adalat.
- Handling the labour related issues and implement strategies for logical conclusion.
- Comprehensive National networking with Legal Professionals, Senior Lawyers, Associates, Consultants etc
- Drafting, Review & Vetting of various Court applications, MOUs, TOS, Indemnities, Litigation Pleadings, etc.
- Overall Central / National Level Monitoring, Tracking, Supervision & Management of Against litigation,
 Crisis Timely Strategy and Action against Fraud with an Objective to Drive Logical Conclusion
- Reporting of Status of Legal Cases & Issues through Customised MIS & Trackers to different platform

April, 2016 till March, 2022:

Promoted as Deputy Manager- HO - Criminal Litigation in Magma Fincorp Ltd. (Renamed as Poonawalla Fincorp Ltd.)

The core job includes dealing against litigation - Civil, Consumer, Criminal Litigations in Courts, Fora, Tribunals & coordination with PAN India team. Report directly to the Vice President (Litigation Head).

Key Activities:

- Litigations & Disputes Resolution
- Advise on initiation of legal case for Statutory and Regulatory Compliances in accordance with audit report & to conduct review of substantial action taken in fraud matter within qickest possible time & recovery efforts made against them.
- Day to Day Support & Advisory Work and Resolution of Queries from Management, Business Functions / Verticals and Branches on all Legal Issues
- Day to Day Advice on Risk Management Strategy

- · Relationship Management & Liaison with External Authorities
- Analysing the impact of various ranges of decree /order passed against the company by different court/forum/tribunals and implementing strategies for dispute resolution including Conciliation, Mediation, Lok Adalat.
- Comprehensive National networking with Legal Professionals, Senior Lawyers, Associates, Consultants etc
- Drafting, Review & Vetting of various Court applications, MOUs, TOS, Indemnities, Litigation Pleadings, etc.
- Overall Central / National Level Monitoring, Tracking, Supervision & Management of Against litigation,
 Crisis Timely Strategy and Action against Fraud
- Reporting of Status of Legal Cases & Issues through Customised MIS & Trackers to different platform

April, 2013 - March, 2016:

Promoted as Assistant Manager - HO - Legal in Magma Fincorp Ltd.

Key Activities:

- Dealing complete solution and disposal of litigation u/s 138.
- Dealing Litigation against Company (mostly Criminal cases filed against Senior management & Employees)

April, 2009 - May, 2013:

Transferred as Executive to Magma, CF Services Pvt. Ltd. (a group company of erstwhile Magma Fincorp Ltd.)

Key Activities:

• Dealing complete solution and disposal of litigation u/s 138.

June, 2008 - March, 2009:

Appointed as Executive (Legal Department) at Magma Converge Solutions Ltd. (a group company of erstwhile Magma Fincorp Ltd.)

Key Activities:

Dealing complete solution and disposal of litigation u/s 138.
